<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hint>
    <metricName>Areas Identifiers</metricName>
    <metricDescription>The proportion of identifiers in the Java code
        relative to the length of the complete code influences its readability.
        Identifiers can be class names method names variable names or labels.
        If you use to many of those in a single method the code will be harder
        to read due to the high density of information.
        You can improve this metric by adding comments / empty lines to the code.
        Unnecessary variable definitions and method calls should also be removed.</metricDescription>
    <goodCodeDescription>This code has a javadoc comment and a comment in the method body.
        There are no unnecessary variables present The method does also
        include some spaces that increase the readability.</goodCodeDescription>
    <goodCode>/**
* Calculates the final price of an item considering a discount and tax rate.
* 
* @param originalPrice the original price of the item (double)
* @param discount the discount percentage as an integer (int)
* @param taxRate the tax rate as a double (double)
* @return true if the final price is above a threshold value
*/
public boolean calculateFinalPrice(double originalPrice, int discount, double taxRate) {

    double discountAmount = originalPrice * discountPercentage / 100;
    double discountedPrice = originalPrice - discountAmount;

    double tax = discountedPrice * taxRate;
    double finalPrice = discountedPrice + tax;

    //threshold is set to 100
    return finalPrice &gt; 100;
}</goodCode>
    <badCodeDescription>Here the method does not hava a javadoc comments or any comments within the method.
        In addition to that plenty of identifiers are used and no spaces are present in the method,
        which increases the identifier / full code ration even more.
        Moreover, the isFinalPriceAboveThreshold is an unnecessary identifier,
        due to the fact, that the boolean expression
        finalPrice &gt; 10 can be returned instantly.</badCodeDescription>
    <badCode>public class Main() {
    public boolean calculateFinalPrice(double originalPrice, int discountPercentage, double taxRate) {
        double discountAmount = originalPrice * discountPercentage / 100;
        double discountedPrice = originalPrice - discountAmount;
        double tax = discountedPrice * taxRate;
        double finalPrice = discountedPrice + tax;
        boolean isFinalPriceAboveThreshold = finalPrice &gt; 100;
        return isFinalPriceAboveThreshold;
    }
}</badCode>
</hint>